Finding Aid for Jabez Thomas Sunderland Papers 1868-1936
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Manuscripts of Books and Articles
  - Centennial Greeting and Message to the Brahmo Somajes in India 1928 (Box 22)
  - The Challenge of Each New Year 1902 (Box 22)
  - Charles Darwin (Box 22)
  - Charles Fletcher Dole 1927 (Box 22)
  - The Civilization and Ideals of Japan 1917 (Box 22)
  - The Civilization and Religion of India 1912 (Box 22)
  - Darwin and Evolution 1933 (Box 22)
  - Dr. Adler on Mahatma Gandhi 1931 (Box 22)
  - Dr. Gannett's Writings (Box 22)
  - Dr. Gilbert Reid and His Unique Mission in China 1927 (Box 22)
  - Dr. Wendte's Remarkable Autobiography 1927 (Box 22)
  - The Doctrine of Original (Box 22)
  - Emerson as a Prophet of World Religion (Box 22)
  - The End of the World, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Excursions Round about Jerusalem, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - The Fascination of Sunsets (Box 23)
  - The Fascination of the Mountains (Box 23)
  - The Fascination of the Sea (Box 23)
  - Four Brahmo Somaj Books (Box 23)
  - From Jerusalem to Damascus on Horseback (Box 23)
  - From Jerusalem to Jericho 1902, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - From London to Jerusalem (Box 23)
  - George Willis Cooke (Box 23)
  - The Glory of Religious Pioneership 1919 (Box 23)
  - God and Miracles (Box 23)
  - God in Life's Deep Experiences 1924 (Box 23)
  - A Golden Travel Year (Box 23)
  - A Great Faith in the Morning of a Great Day, 5 folders (Box 23)
  - Great Leaders of Liberal Religion (Box 23)
  - Great Religions of Asia (Box 23)
  - The Great Religions of Mankind, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - A Great Woman of India (Box 23)
  - Historic and Religious India (Box 23)
  - The Historic "Issue in the West" and "Humanism" (Box 23)
  - How the World Got its Sacred Books or Bibles 1928 (Box 23)
  - The Impending Crisis in India 1929 (Box 23)
  - India and Japan: A Comparison (Box 23)
  - India in Bondage 1928 (Box 23)
  - India in Bondage (British Edition), 3 folders (Box 23)
  - India in Bondage (British Edition), 4 folders (Box 24)
  - India's "Pax Britannica" (Box 24)
  - Is Evolution True? (Box 24)
  - Is India Fit For Self-Rule Now? (Box 24)
  - Is Unitarian Christianity the World's Hope?, 2 copies (Box 24)
  - James Martineau (Box 24)
  - Japanese Art (Box 24)
  - Jenkin Lloyd Jones and the Orient (Box 24)
  - Jesus as a World Ideal (Box 24)
  - John Ruskin (Box 24)
  - A Journey Through Palestine 1901 (Box 24)
  - The June Glory (Box 24)
  - Just What Was "The Issue in the West" (Box 24)
  - Just Why Does India Reject British Rule (Box 24)
  - Lecture on Ventilation 1875 (Box 24)
  - Liberal Religion in the Orient (Box 24)
  - Liberal Religion: The World's Certainly Coming Faith, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - The Maha-Bharta (Box 24)
  - Man's Infinite Need of God (Box 24)
  - Man's Mightiest Need (Box 24)
  - Matthew Arnold (Box 24)
  - Millions for Unitarianism, But What About World Service (Box 24)
  - The Modern View of Salvation (Box 24)
  - Mohammedanism and Unitarianism (Box 24)
  - The Moral Dynamic of Liberal Religion (Box 24)
  - A Morning Ride in Ceylon (Box 24)
  - Mrs. Naider and Mr. Andrews in America (Box 24)
  - My Trip to California in 1894 (Box 24)
  - My Visit to Benares (Box 24)
  - The Need of World-Wide Religious Brotherhood (Box 24)
  - The New and Better Bible 1935 (Box 24)
  - New Bible Talks 1927 (Box 24)
  - New Scriptures 1930 (Box 24)
  - Open Letter to Mahatma Gandhi 1924 (Box 24)
  - The Other Side of the Medal (Box 24)
  - Our Friends, the Trees (Box 24)
  - The Personality of Tagore (Box 24)
  - Picturesque India 1912 (Box 24)
  - Report on the Mission to the Orient 1913-1914 (Box 24)
  - The Planting of the Unity Acorn 1928 (Box 24)
  - Political Education and the Grange (Box 24)
  - A Prayer for India 1930 (Box 24)
  - Present Political Conditions in China 1916 (Box 24)
  - Rabindranath Tagore as an Educator (Box 24)
  - A Religion for Free Nations and Free Men (Box 24)
  - A Religion that Dares to Trust Truth (Box 24)
  - A Review of Financial Operations of the Government (Box 25)
  - Rising Japan 1917 (Box 25)
  - Robert Browning (Box 25)
  - Robert Browning: His Central Message (Box 25)
  - Robert Burns (Box 25)
  - Second Coming of Christ (Box 25)
  - Short Articles on Unitarianism, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Should not the Meadville School Be Moved to Chicago (Box 25)
  - Some Honored and Beloved Unitarian "Methuselahs" (Box 25)
  - The Soul's Cry for God (Box 25)
  - The Story of Liberal Religion in Europe (Box 25)
  - The Story of "The Three Rings" (Box 25)
  - A Sunrise Service of the Isles of Shoals (Box 25)
  - The Supreme Idiocy (Box 25)
  - The Things That Endure (Box 25)
  - Trees as God's Poems (Box 25)
  - Trees as Teachers (Box 25)
  - Trip to Palestine, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Trips to Historic Places (Box 25)
  - Trustworthy Indian History (Box 25)
  - The Truth About the Mutiny (Box 25)
  - Two Eminent American Women 1931 (Box 25)
  - Two Months in Japan 1914 (Box 25)
  - Two Weeks in Jerusalem, 4 folders (Box 25)
  - Unique Missionary Tours in India (Box 25)
  - The Unitarian Appraisal (Box 25)
  - Unitarianism and India (Box 25)
  - Unitarianism and the Bible (Box 25)
  - Unitarianism and Theism (Box 25)
  - A Uniting and Unsectarian Religion (Box 25)
  - Unity as Prophet and Pioneer (Box 25)
  - Wealth, Beauty and Youth for All (Box 25)
  - Wealth for Everybody (Box 25)
  - Were Unitarians the First to Accept and Preach Evolution (Box 25)
  - What is India (Box 25)
  - What Shall We Teach Our Children About Santa Claus (Box 25)
  - What Should Sundays Be in a Civilized Land (Box 25)
  - Where Poets Find God (Box 25)
  - Why India Boycotted the Simon Commission, 4 folders (Box 25)
  - Why India Rejects the Simon Report (Box 25)
  - Why Modern Religion is Abandoning Miracles 1926 (Box 25)
  - Why Study the Bible, 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Why Study the Bible (Box 26)
  - Why We Should Know about India (Box 26)
  - A Wider Field for the Christian Register (Box 26)
  - Will the Unitarian Faith Prevail, 4 folders (Box 26)
  - World Brotherhood, 7 folders (Box 26)
  - The World's Seven Great Historic Religions (Box 26)
- Research Notes and Manuscripts
  - Research Notes on Liberal Religion, 16 folders (Box 26)
  - Research Notes on Liberal Religion, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Manuscripts on "The Bible in the Light of Modern Knowledge" 1905, 12 folders (Box 27)
  - Newspaper clippings re. India in Bondage, 1928-1930, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Testimonials concerning India in Bondage, 1929-1930 (Box 27)
  - Reviews of books by Sunderland 1888-1923, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Reviews of books by Sunderland 1888-1923, 2 folders (Box 28)
- Printed Materials
  - A College Town Pulpit, 1894-1896 (Box 28)
  - A College Town Pulpit, 1897-1898 (Box 28)
  - A Pacific Coast Pulpit, 1899 (Box 28)
  - Twentieth Century Sermons (Box 28)
  - Pamphlets on India 1896-1930, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Pamphlets 1875-1933, 4 folders (Box 28)
  - Pamphlets undated, 5 folders (Box 28)
  - Minister's Hand-Book: For Christenings, Weddings, and Funerals, by M. J. Savage (Boston: George H. Ellis, 1889), heavily annotated by Sunderland (Box 28)
  - Bound pamphlets
    - A College Town Pulpit (Box 28)
      (2 copies, one with inscription, the other with some annotations)
    - Sunderland Pamphlets (Box 28)
      (bound 1930 for the Unitarian Church of Ann Arbor)
    - A Ministry in a College Town, 1878-1898 (Box 28)
      (2 volumes and a second variant copy of volume 2)
  - The Unitarian, bound volumes, 1886-1897 (Box 29)
    (volumes 1-12)
  - Books by Jabez T. Sunderland (many with annotations)
    - Because Men Are Not Stones (Boston: Beacon Press, 1923) (2 copies, one partially revised for a new edition to be titled Man's Infinite Need of God) (Box 49)
    - Eminent Americans: Whom India Should Know (Calcutta: R. Chatterjee, 1935) (Box 49)
    - Grains of Gold (Ann Arbor, Mich.: George Wahr, undated) (Box 49)
    - India, America and World Brotherhood (Madras: Ganesh & Co., 1924) (Box 49)
    - India In Bondage: Her Right to Freedom and a Place Among the Great Nations (New York: Lewis Copeland, 1929) (Box 49)
    - L'Inde Enchainée (Paris: Presses Universitaires, undated) (Box 49)
    - Shikkoku no indo (Tokyo: Heibonsha, 1933) (Box 49)
    - Jesus and His Cross (no publisher, no date) (Box 49)
    - The Liberal Christian Ministry (Boston: Geo. H. Ellis, 1889) (Box 49)
    - Oh, To Be Rich and Young! (Boston: American Unitarian Association, 1910) (Box 49)
    - One Upward Look Each Day: Poems of Hope and Courage (Ann Arbor, Mich.: George Wahr, 1923) (Box 49)
    - The Origin and Character of the Bible: And Its Place among Sacred Books (Boston: American Unitarian Association, 1908) (Box 49)
    - Orthodoxy and Revivalism: Sermons on Vital Questions at Issue between Popular Evangelical Christianity, Especially as Represented by the Revivalism of Messrs. Moody and Sankey, and the Rational Religious Thought of the Time (New York: James Miller, 1877) (Box 49)
    - Religion and Evolution: A Series of Six Sermons (Toronto: Unitarian Club of Toronto, undated) (Box 49)
    - Rising Japan: Is She a Menace or a Comrade to be Welcomed in the Fraternity of Nations? (New York: Putnam's, 1918) (Box 49)
    - Travel and Life in Palestine: A Young People's Excursion Through the Lands of the Bible (London: Sunday School Association, undated) (Box 49)
    - Wealth, Beauty and Youth for All (Madras: Ganesh & Co., undated) (Box 49)
  - Unitarian pamphlets 1886-1887, 2 volumes (Box 50)
  - Pamphlets by other ministers, 5 folders (Box 50)
  - Memorial and Biographical Sketches, by James Freeman Clarke (Boston: Houghton, Osgood, 1880) (Box 50)
  - Unity Mission, bound volume containing no. 4, 13, 15, 18, 19, 20, 21, and Unity Church Door Pulpit, series 2, no. 16, 20 (Box 50)
- Topical Files on India
  - American Economic Interests in India (Box 30)
  - American Exclusion of Indians (Box 30)
  - The Amritsar Massacre (Box 30)
  - Andrews, Rev. Charles F. (Box 30)
  - The Army and Defense, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Bajpai, Ramlal (Box 30)
  - Bannerji, Surenda Nath (Box 30)
  - Barbarities, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Baroda (Box 30)
  - Barr, Rev. Margaret (Box 30)
  - Basu, B.B. (Box 30)
  - Benares, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Benefits of British Rule (Box 30)
  - Bengal (Box 30)
  - Besant, Anni (Box 30)
  - Bhandarkar, R.G. (Box 30)
  - Birth Rate (Box 30)
  - Black Hole of Calcutta (Box 30)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone (Box 30)
  - Bombay (Box 30)
  - Bombs and Terrorism (Box 30)
  - Bonner, H.B. (Box 30)
  - Bonnerjee, W.C. (Box 30)
  - Bose, Amanda (Box 30)
  - Bose, Professor J.C. (Box 30)
  - Bose, Sudhindra (Box 30)
  - Boycott (Box 30)
  - Bright, John (Box 30)
  - British Colonies (Box 30)
  - British Efforts to Get American Support for Her Policies (Box 30)
  - British Labor Party (Box 30)
  - British Rule (Box 30)
  - Broken Promises (Box 30)
  - Bryan, William Jennings (Box 30)
  - Burma (Box 30)
  - Calcutta (Box 30)
  - Capital for Industry (Box 30)
  - Castes, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Chakrabarti, Nilmani (Box 30)
  - Chaitanya, Sree (Box 31)
  - Chandravarkar, Narayan (Box 31)
  - Chatterjee, Ramananda (Box 31)
  - Chatterji, B.C. (Box 31)
  - Christianity in India (Box 31)
  - Civil Disobedience (Box 31)
  - Civil Service (Box 31)
  - Colour Line in India (Box 31)
  - The Conquest of India (Box 31)
  - Constitution for India (Box 31)
  - Cooch, Behar (Box 31)
  - Co-operative Societies (Box 31)
  - Cotton, Sir Henry (Box 31)
  - Courts and Law, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Currency (Box 31)
  - Curtis, Lionel (Box 31)
  - Curzon, Lord (Box 31)
  - Das, C.R. (Box 31)
  - Das, Taraknath (Box 31)
  - Datta, Aswini K. (Box 31)
  - Datta, Satyendranath (Box 31)
  - Dayanand, Sariswati (Box 31)
  - Death (Box 31)
  - Decentralization (Box 31)
  - Defense (Box 31)
  - Degradation of the Indian People by British Rule (Box 31)
  - Delhi (Box 31)
  - Democracy in India (Box 31)
  - Deportations (Box 31)
  - Depressed Classes Mission Society, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Devi, Sushila (Box 31)
  - Dominion Status (Box 31)
  - Durbar (Box 31)
  - Dutt, Toru and R.C. (Box 31)
  - Dyer, General (Box 31)
  - Education, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Egypt (Box 31)
  - Exploitation of India (Box 31)
  - Famines (Box 31)
  - Famines, 4 folders (Box 32)
  - Fife, Hamilton (Box 32)
  - Finances and the Public Debt (Box 32)
  - Forests and Forestry (Box 32)
  - France and India (Box 32)
  - Freedom of Speech and Press (Box 32)
  - Friends of Freedom for India (Box 32)
  - Friends of India in England (Box 32)
  - Frontier Wars (Box 32)
  - Future of India (Box 32)
  - Gadar Party (Box 32)
  - Gandhi, Mahatma (Box 32)
  - Geneva International Conference (Box 32)
  - Government of India Act (Box 32)
  - Gregg, Richard B. (Box 32)
  - Grievances of the Indians (Box 32)
  - Gupta, Kedar Nath Das (Box 32)
  - Gurukul at Hardwar (Box 32)
  - Imperial Federation (Box 32)
  - India Academy of America (Box 32)
  - India Home Rule League of America (Box 32)
  - India Society of America (Box 32)
  - India's Place in Civilization, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Indian Councils Act of 1909 (Box 32)
  - Indian National Congress (Box 32)
  - Indian Navy (Box 32)
  - Indians in Canada (Box 32)
  - Indians in Other British Colonies (Box 32)
  - Java (Box 32)
  - Karve, Professor D.K. (Box 32)
  - Kalkar, N.C. (Box 32)
  - Kenya (Box 32)
  - Halifat (Box 32)
  - Khasi Hills Unitarian Union, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Khilofat Conference (Box 32)
  - Kitchener, Lord (Box 32)
  - Knight, Robert (Box 32)
  - Korea (Box 32)
  - Krishnavarma, Shyamaji (Box 32)
  - Labor Conditions in India (Box 32)
  - League of Nations (Box 32)
  - New Delhi (Box 33)
  - Opium (Box 33)
  - Propaganda (Box 33)
  - Ratter, Magnus C. (Box 33)
  - Religion, 4 folders (Box 33)
  - South Africa (Box 33)
  - Miscellanea, 3 folders (Box 33)
- Miscellaneous Papers and Notebooks
  - Papers concerning a book on nature called "The Glorious Outdoors" (Box 33)
  - Papers concerning a book on nature called "The Glorious Outdoors" (Box 34)
  - Papers concerning a book on nature called "The Glorious Outdoors" (Box 35)
  - Papers concerning the Sunderland testimonial dinner 1932 (Box 35)
  - Letters and cards received upon his ninetieth birthday 1932, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Letters and cards received upon his ninety-fourth birthday 1936 (Box 35)
  - Papers concerning his Civil War Pension 1903-1935 (Box 35)
  - Newspaper clippings concerning education undated, 1880-1883, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Newspaper clippings concerning women and the ministry 1920-1929 (Box 35)
  - Manuscript sermons by Robert Collyer 1877, 1887 (Box 35)
  - Papers, miscellaneous undated, 5 folders (Box 35)
  - Papers on miscellaneous subjects, in chronological order 1868-1909, 7 folders (Box 35)
  - Papers on miscellaneous subjects, in chronological order 1910-1936, 4 folders (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets on India collected by Sunderland (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks (Box 36)
  - Correspondence regarding The Unitarian Magazine, 1890 (Box 36)
  - Manuscript entitled "The Western Issue" circa 1922 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous topical files on India (Box 36)
  - Manuscript of The Story of Liberal Religion in Europe (Box 36)
  - Manuscripts of Articles, 7 folders (Box 36)
  - Manuscripts of Articles, 1 folders (Box 37)
  - Copies of The Modern Review, Calcutta, containing Sunderland Articles, 1936-1942 (Box 37)
    (20 issues)
  - Book lists (Box 37)
  - Miscellanea (Box 37)
- Biographical/Autobiographical Material
  - Biographical Material 1877-1936, 4 folders (Box 37)
  - Autobiographical Material, 4 folders (Box 37)
  - Notes and Clippings for Autobiography (Box 37)
  - Biographies of Jabez T. Sunderland and of his mother, Sarah Broadhead Sunderland 1989, 1963 (Box 37)
  - Obituaries and Memorials of Sunderland 1936-1943
- Topical File
  This series is arranged alphabetically by personal name or subject heading given to it by Jabez Sunderland. In the processing of this series, miscellaneous smaller files have been drawn together (within each letter) into broader categories, usually including Publications, Social Issues, India, Sunderland sermons and articles, and Unitarianism. Stray correspondence has also been broken out with noteworthy correspondents noted. This series is an excellent source of published sermon and pamphlet material on topics of general social and political interest and of special value in researching the doctrines and theology of Unitarianism. This file was originally given to Meadville/Lombard Theological School and was transferred to the Bentley Historical Library in 2005.
  - A (Box 38)
    - Abbott, Alonzo F (Box 38)
      (letter and newspaper obituary)
    - Ashley, J. M., publications (Box 38)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 38)
    - Social issues (Box 38)
      (include Armenian massacre and relief)
    - Unitarianism (Box 38)
      (published tracts and sermons on A topics or by A authors)
  - B
    - Baptism (Box 38)
    - Bellows, H.W. (about) (Box 38)
    - Bible (Box 38)
    - Birth Control (Box 38)
    - Blackwell, Alice Stone (Box 38)
      (correspondence and miscellaneous)
    - Bose, J.C. (Box 38)
    - Boynton, R. W. (sermons) (Box 38)
    - Boys Clubs and related Boys (Box 38)
    - Buddha and Buddhism (Box 38)
    - Burns, Robert (Box 38)
    - Correspondence (Box 38)
    - India (Box 38)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 38)
    - Sunderland (Box 38)
      (B topics: sermons, clippings, and articles; selective drafts of articles and addresses)
    - Unitarianism (Box 38)
      (published tracts and sermons on B topics or by B authors)
  - C
    - Carnegie, Andrew (Box 38)
      (draft of letter to AC and manuscript of article about AC and India)
    - Chancellor, H.G. (Box 38)
      (correspondence and pamphlets)
    - Chant, Laura Ormiston (Box 38)
      (photograph portraits, pamphlets, miscellaneous)
    - Chapman, J Wilbur (Box 38)
      (letter about and ephemera)
    - Chatterjee, Ramananda (Box 38)
      (correspondence and JTS article about)
    - Child labor and children's aid (Box 38)
    - Collegiate Alumnae, Association of (Box 38)
      (published material)
    - Cooke, George W. (Box 38)
      (correspondence, JTS article about, and miscellaneous)
    - Correspondence (Box 38)
      (include C.W. Casson, C. Carrothers, Mary Louise Catlin)
    - Crooker, Joseph Henry (Box 38)
      (pamphlets and tracts)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 39)
    - Social issues (Box 39)
      (pamphlets)
    - Sunderland (Box 39)
      (C topics: sermons, clippings, and articles; selective drafts of articles and addresses)
    - Unitarianism, 2 folders (Box 39)
      (published tracts and sermons on C topics or by C authors)
  - D
    - Correspondence (Box 39)
    - Das, Taraknath (Box 39)
      (correspondence and published material)
    - Death (Box 39)
      (pamphlets about)
    - Denslow, Henry C. (Box 39)
      (correspondence)
    - Devil (Box 39)
    - Dewey, John (Box 39)
      (brief letter, March 1930)
    - Douthit, Jasper, 2 folders (Box 39)
      (correspondence and published materials)
    - Durant, Will (Box 39)
    - India (Box 39)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 39)
    - Social issues (Box 39)
    - Sunderland (Box 39)
      (D topics: sermons, clippings, and articles; selective drafts of articles and addresses)
    - Sunderland, J. T. (Box 39)
      (correspondence, clippings, and related material pertaining to essay "The Drift of the Age")
    - Unitarian Drive for Two Million Dollars 1920 (Box 39)
    - Unitarianism, 1 folders (Box 39)
      (published tracts and sermons on D topics or by D authors)
  - E
    - Correspondence (Box 40)
    - Education (Box 40)
    - Edwards, Rev. David (Box 40)
    - Eliot (Charles W. and George W.) (Box 40)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 40)
    - Sunderland (Box 40)
      (E topics: programs and ephemera)
    - Unitarianism, 2 folders (Box 40)
      (published tracts and sermons on E topics or by E authors)
  - F
    - Federation-National Federation of Religious Liberals (Box 40)
    - Furness, Prof. Caroline (Box 40)
      (astronomer, letter written from India, 1927)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 40)
    - Social issues (Box 40)
    - Sunderland (Box 40)
      (F topics: sermons, clippings, and articles; selective drafts of articles and addresses)
    - Unitarianism, 1 folders (Box 40)
      (published tracts and sermons on F topics or by F authors)
  - G
    - Correspondence (Box 40)
      (include letters of Zona Gale, Eleanor Elizabeth Gordon, K.N. Das Gupta)
    - Gannett, William C. (Box 40)
    - India (Box 40)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 40)
    - Social issues (Box 40)
    - Sunderland (Box 40)
      (G topics: miscellaneous)
    - Unitarianism (Box 40)
      (published tracts and sermons on G topics or by G authors)
  - H
    - Correspondence (Box 40)
    - Huxley, Thomas (Box 40)
      (pamphlets by and about)
    - India (Box 40)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 40)
    - Social issues (Box 41)
    - Sunderland (Box 41)
      (H topics: pamphlets; also essay "The Higher Patriotism-The Cuban and Spanish Wars, 1899")
    - Unitarianism, 1 folders (Box 41)
      (published tracts and sermons on H topics or by H authors)
  - I
    - Correspondence (Box 41)
      (include Irving Winslow of the Anti-Imperialist League and letters regarding immigration of East Indian immigrants)
    - Immortality (Box 41)
    - India (Box 41)
    - India House of New York/Society for the Advancement of India (Box 41)
    - Ingersoll, Robert (Box 41)
      (pamphlets by and about; also JTS essay on Ingersoll with related correspondence)
    - Institute of Politics (Box 41)
      (include correspondence of Harry A. Garfield, John Haynes Holmes)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 41)
    - Social issues (Box 41)
    - Sunderland (Box 41)
      (I topics: miscellaneous, including address "Present Religious Conditions in India)
    - Unitarianism (Box 41)
      (published tracts and sermons on I topics or by I authors)
  - J
    - Correspondence (Box 42)
    - India (Box 42)
    - Jesus (Box 42)
      (pamphlets and correspondence)
    - Jews and Judaism (Box 42)
    - Juvenile courts (Box 42)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 42)
    - Sunderland (Box 42)
      (include pamphlet Jesus as Humanity's Ideal; manuscript of essay, "Imperialism as a Peril to the Republic")
    - Unitarianism (Box 42)
      (published tracts and sermons on J topics or by J authors)
  - K
    - Correspondence (Box 42)
    - India (correspondence photographs, and other materials relating to the Khasi and Jaintia Hills Unitarian Union) (Box 42)
    - King's Daughters (Box 42)
    - Publications (various topics) (Box 42)
    - Social issues (Box 42)
    - Unitarianism (Box 42)
      (published tracts and sermons on K topics or by K authors)
  - L
    - Correspondence (Box 42)
    - Liberal religion (Box 42)
    - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 42)
    - Publication (various topics) (Box 42)
    - Social issues (Box 42)
      (include lynching)
    - Sunderland (Box 42)
      (published sermons, essay on Abraham Lincoln)
    - Unitarianism (Box 42)
      (published tracts and sermons on L topics or by L authors)
  - M
    - Correspondence (Box 43)
    - India (Box 43)
    - Meadville Theological Seminary (Box 43)
    - Miracles (Box 43)
    - Mozoomdar, P.C. (Box 43)
    - Published (various topics) (Box 43)
    - Religions (Mormon and other non-Unitarian) (Box 43)
    - Social issues (Box 43)
    - Sunderland (Box 43)
      (published sermons, manuscripts, clippings)
    - Sunderland-manuscript of "Militarism: the War Spirit, the World Prospect for Peace" (Box 43)
    - Unitarianism, 2 folders (Box 43)
      (published tracts and sermons on M topics or by M authors)
  - N
    - Correspondence (Box 43)
    - Nagarkar, B.B (Box 43)